smartusa.com 2019-05-17

# Privacy Statement | Mercedes-Benz USA

Learn about the information we collect through the MBUSA platform, how we use that information, and your options for participation. 

Effective: February 6, 2018 

This Privacy Statement explains the privacy practices of Mercedes-Benz USA, LLC, its affiliates, and subsidiaries (collectively “MBUSA”) related to your access and use of MBUSA’s family of websites and widgets (collectively, “Sites”) and our mobile phone, tablet, and other smart device applications (collectively, “Applications”). The Sites and Applications are collectively referred to in this Privacy Statement as the “MBUSA Platform.” In this Privacy Statement, “we,” “us,” and “our,” refer collectively to MBUSA.

This Privacy Statement does _not_ address our connected vehicle services privacy practices. Our connected vehicle services privacy practices are addressed in our Connected Vehicle Services section. Our smart device applications also contain additional privacy information about specific application functionalities, which can be found in our Mobile Applications section or within the information section of our Applications.

The MBUSA Platform is targeted to individuals in the United States and Puerto Rico. If you access the MBUSA Platform from other regions, be aware that the privacy practices of MBUSA may differ from those of your home country. By interacting with the MBUSA Platform, you are accepting the terms of this Privacy Statement. If you do not accept the terms of this Privacy Statement, do not use the MBUSA Platform.

Some features of the MBUSA Platform ask you to provide us with specific categories of information in order to enjoy complete functionality. If you do not provide us with the categories of information requested, your ability to fully interact with the MBUSA Platform may be limited. The features requiring you to provide information to MBUSA are described in detail below:

**Inquiries**

In order to submit inquiries through the MBUSA Platform, you must provide certain information. The “Contact a Dealership,” “Schedule a Test Drive,” and “Request a Quote,” forms require you to provide your name and email address. This information is required so that you can be contacted about your request. Some MBUSA Platform forms also require you to provide us with your geographic region or zip code so that we can direct your request appropriately.

The “Apply for Credit” form requires you to provide your name, address, date of birth, phone number, email address, social security number, and employment information. This information is required in order to determine your creditworthiness and to notify you of the results of your credit application.

**Sweepstakes, Promotions, Contests & Surveys**

In order to participate in sweepstakes, promotions, or contests on the MBUSA Platform, you are required to provide personal information such as your name, street address, email address, and date of birth. We require this information in order to administer the sweepstakes, promotions, and contests, to ensure participants meet applicable eligibility requirements, and to contact winners.

You may be asked to participate in surveys about your experience with the MBUSA Platform. When participating in surveys, any information you provide in the comments field will be shared with us, so please do not include any sensitive personal information or other information you do not wish to share.

**Placing an Order**

When you place an order or reserve a vehicle on the MBUSA Platform, you are required to provide information necessary to fulfill that order or secure your deposit, including your name, address, phone number, and payment information. We use a third-party service to process orders, deposits, and payments. For more information, please review the “Information Sharing” section of this Privacy Statement.

**Account Registration**

When you register for an account with our Sites or our Applications, you must provide your name and email address. You also have the option to allow MBUSA to contact you with information about products or services that may be of interest to you. Once your account is established, you have the option to provide us with additional information such as your address and phone number so that we can pre-populate forms on the MBUSA Platform when you are logged in. You will also have the ability to save vehicle configurations and inventory favorites in your account. We store that information for as long as your account is active.

You may modify your accounts at any time by visiting the “Profile” settings and making changes to individual fields. You may delete your account at any time by using the “Delete My Account” link in your profile settings. Or you can contact us to modify or delete your account.

**Applications**

When you use our Applications, you may grant certain permissions for MBUSA to obtain information from your smart device such as your location and access to your device’s camera or photos. Please consult your device manufacturer for information on how to view or modify these permissions, but note that doing so may limit the functionality of Application features.

In order to enjoy certain features of our Applications, you will need to provide us with the VIN from your Mercedes vehicle. This will allow us to provide you with applicable manuals, videos, connect you with a Product Concierge, and remind you of scheduled service and maintenance. On applicable models, providing your VIN will also allow you to remotely lock or unlock your vehicle, start your vehicle, play sound from your device through your vehicle, and access your vehicle’s location, mileage, and fuel information.

You may also link your Mercedes-Benz Financial Services account with your Mercedes me account using your social security number. MBUSA does not store your social security number when you use this function.

Additional information about the information you provide to us through individual Applications is available within each’s Application’s information section and here.

**Tracking Technologies**

We use cookies and other tracking technologies to personalize your experience, analyze user trends, and improve the MBUSA Platform. These tracking technologies allow us to collect information such as your device type, browser type, time spent on our websites, pages visited, geographic location, and other data. You can alter the configuration of your browser to refuse to accept cookies, but it is possible that doing so may cause limited functionality of the MBUSA Platform. For example, we may not be able to recognize your computer or device, and you may need to log in every time you visit.

**Do Not Track**

The MBUSA Platform does not respond to “Do Not Track” signals at this time.

**Applications**

Please review the privacy statement of your device manufacturer and the privacy statement applicable to each Application for information about the data automatically collected when you use our Applications.

We also obtain information about the traffic and usage of the MBUSA Platform from third parties, including Google, Kenshoo, and Shift Digital. These third parties also use cookies and other tracking technologies to capture information about your interactions with the MBUSA Platform. MBUSA does not have control over the information that is collected, used, and shared by these third parties. We encourage you to review the privacy statements of these third parties to understand their privacy practices.

**Inquiries**

When you complete the “Contact a Dealership,” “Schedule a Test Drive,” or “Request a Quote,” forms, we share this information with authorized dealerships so they can contact you about your request and provide you with information about services and products that may meet your needs. When you complete the “Apply for Credit” form, your information is shared with Mercedes-Benz Financial Services so that it can review your credit application. Information about Mercedes-Benz Financial Services’ privacy practices are available [here](https://www.mbfs.com/mbfsr/en/misc/trademarkDisclaimerStatement.do).

**Sweepstakes, Promotions, Contests & Surveys**

We use third party service providers to manage MBUSA Platform-based sweepstakes, promotions, and contests, and to conduct surveys about your experience using the MBUSA Platform. When you enter sweepstakes, promotions, and contests or complete surveys on the MBUSA Platform, your information is shared with our service providers.

**Placing an Order**

We use a third party service provider to manage our Lifestyle Collection website and to manage deposit payments when you reserve a vehicle. Information you provide when making online purchases is shared with our third party service providers so that your payment can be processed and your order can be fulfilled.

**Account Registration**

When you register an account on the MBUSA Platform, MBUSA does not maintain your password. That information is stored on Daimler’s customer identity and access management system. Some of our connected vehicle application features are managed by third party service providers.

**Third Party Links**

The MBUSA Platform contains links to other websites such as social media platforms, other Mercedes-Benz websites, and event and partner websites. These websites are not covered by MBUSA’s Privacy Statement. Please review the Privacy Statements of these websites in order to understand the privacy practices of these third parties.

**Applications**

Please review the privacy statement of your device manufacturer and the privacy statement applicable to each Application for information about the data shared from our Applications.

**Other**

Aside from the instances described above, we will only share your personal information: to comply with the law; to respond to claims; to comply with legal process served on MBUSA or our parent company Daimler AG (e.g., a lawful subpoena, warrant, or court order); to enforce or apply our policies or agreements; (including to bill and collect payments); to protect and defend our rights or property or that of our dealers, customers, employees, visitors, or the public; in connection with a business transfer, sale, liquidation, or merger; and if we reasonably believe that an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person requires disclosure; with your consent.

The MBUSA Platform is neither designed for nor targeted to children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, do not provide your personal information through the MBUSA Platform. If you believe your child has impermissibly provided us with their personal information, please contact us, so that we can identify and delete their information.

We use commercially reasonable administrative, technical, and physical safeguards to protect personal information collected through the MBUSA Platform.

We retain the information we collect for as long as reasonably necessary to provide services and fulfill the purposes described in this Privacy Statement.

If you have comments, questions, or concerns about this Privacy Statement or about MBUSA’s collection, use, or disclosure of your personal information, or if you would like to make a request to review or update your personal information, please contact us using one of the following methods:

_Email_ : 

Attention: Privacy Officer

One Mercedes-Benz Drive

Sandy Springs, GA 30328

MBUSA may update or change this Privacy Statement from time to time and without prior notice to you. The top of this Privacy Statement will indicate when it was most recently updated.
